DELICIOUS IN DUNGEON
《迷宮飯》
I'm back, Mom.
我回來了，媽媽
What's that?
你在煮什麼？
It smells great.
味道好香喔
That's because it's your birthday.
今天是你的生日
It's all your favorite dishes.
煮的都是你喜歡吃的料理
Wow, really?
天啊，真的嗎？
Time to eat up.
多吃點喔
See? These are all your favorite…
你看，全都是你最喜歡吃的…
ingredients from the dungeon.
是在迷宮捕獲的食材
What's wrong, Marcille?
怎麼了？瑪露希爾
I had a nightmare.
我剛才做了惡夢
What's with this smell?
這陣香味是怎麼回事？
It's the same as in my dream.
跟夢中一模一樣
Another party is making breakfast over there.
別的隊伍在那邊做早餐
They're grilling cured pork
他們將鹽漬豬肉用火炙烤
and eating it.
然後享用
I'm so jealous.
好羨慕喔
How truly terrible.
糟糕透頂
It's just so tragic.
實在很可悲
100 PERSON SURVEY ON DUNGEON MEALS
（訪問百名冒險者的迷宮飯）
When it comes to meals eaten by young adventurers nowadays,
說起最近年輕冒險者的飲食
they have bread, dried meat, and wine.
不外乎就是麵包、肉乾及葡萄酒
To build up stamina for exploring the dungeon,
探索迷宮需要增加體力
fat from meats is important.
攝取肉類脂肪確實重要
But that alone is not enough.
光是那樣可不行
Malnutrition is more terrifying than monsters.
營養不良比魔物還要可怕
This may sound like a lecture,
雖然講了一堆大道理
but that doesn't mean our meals are perfect either.
其實我們也沒有攝取營養均衡的飲食
The young elven girl says she's jealous of their pork,
剛才精靈女孩看到豬肉表示很羨慕
but that's because her body wants fat.
那是因為你的身體渴望脂肪
I just don't want to eat monsters!
我只是不想吃魔物！
And so,
因此呢
we'll hunt monsters high in fat today.
我們今天就來獵捕脂肪豐富的魔物
If we can find eggs, that's even better.
若能採集到蛋會更好
Eggs have all the nutrition you need.
蛋是完全營養品
We should proactively harvest them in the dungeon.
在迷宮裡最好積極取得
Are you thinking…
所以你是指那個吧…
Yeah, I am.
對，沒錯
What is it?
是哪個？
The body of a chicken.
擁有雞身
The tail of a snake.
還有蛇尾
A creature said to possess deadly venom in its fangs and claws.
尖牙和銳爪都具有猛毒的
The Basilisk, king of snakes.
蛇中之王巴西利斯克
Oh, a Basilisk.
哦，原來是巴西利斯克啊
Isn't that great, Marcille?
太好了，瑪露希爾
You'll get to eat chicken.
可以吃到雞肉了
Is that chicken? Does that really count as chicken?
你說雞肉？那也稱得上是雞肉嗎？
Isn't it so cool?
很帥吧？
I used to think it was cooler when more species are mixed together.
以前我也認為 混合越多種生物的魔物越帥
But with only two types, they bring out each other's strengths.
到頭來還是混合兩種生物的最帥 能互相提升彼此的魅力
I even noticed the beauty of chicken, something I used to only see as poultry.
以往只把雞當作家禽看待的我 也重新發現雞的魅力
It's a simple yet profound combination.
真的是簡單又深奧的組合
By the way, the Cockatrice that nests deeper inside
補充說明，住在迷宮更深層的雞蛇
is another kind of snake-tailed animal.
則是另一種尾蛇類
I've always dreamed of comparing its taste with a Basilisk's.
比較雞蛇與巴西利斯克的滋味 是我長久以來的夢想
Why would anyone want that?
為何會有那種欲望啊？
That area is a Basilisk nest.
那一帶就是巴西利斯克的巢穴
There it is.
找到了
Looks like they're freshly laid.
似乎是最近剛產下的卵
Let's snatch them up while their mother's gone.
趁凶惡的母獸不在時搜刮卵吧
They're so long and narrow.
卵怎麼那麼細長？
Hold this.
拿好囉
It's so soft.
好軟喔
A Basilisk cry.
是巴西利斯克的威嚇聲
Let's hurry, Senshi.
動作快，先西
Wait, we got to wrap this in cloth.
等等，要用布把卵包起來
It's the party from earlier.
是剛才的隊伍
That's the worst way to run away.
那種逃法最糟糕
She's basically begging to get her back kicked.
簡直像是對敵人說快來踹背
Go and save her already!
趕快救她啦！
Spread your arms and legs out to make your body look as big as possible
張開手腳，盡可能使身體顯得巨大
and make loud sounds to intimidate it.
發出巨大聲響威嚇對方
That'll stop it from coming any further!
只要這麼做 自然就不會被對方拉近距離！
I want to pretend that I'm not associated with him.
真想裝作不認識他
Basilisks also have a head on their tail.
巴西利斯克頭尾兩端都有頭
It doesn't seem to have a blind spot, but it only has one body.
乍看下毫無死角，但身體只有一個
If you bait the heads with an attack from two different directions,
只要從不同方向同時攻擊 藉此引起對方注意
the two brains will confuse the body…
兩側的大腦會導致…
for a single moment.
身體在那瞬間陷入混亂
How are his wounds?
傷勢如何？
Was he poisoned?
看來他中毒了？
-Y-Yes. -Laios.
-對 -萊歐斯
Senshi says he has an antidote.
先西說有解毒藥
Really?
真的嗎？
I want to use it in today's cooking.
老夫打算將這個當作今天的食材
-What?!
-什麼？
But this guy's hanging on by a thread!
你沒看到他都快死了嗎？
Instead of taking the antidote alone,
與其單吃解毒藥
it's tastier when cooked.
經過調理後會比較好吃
Then cook it already!
那就趕快做！
First, cut off the tail and feet.
首先將尾巴及腳切掉
Blanch it a bit and pluck its feathers.
稍微川燙後拔除羽毛
It's chicken now.
現在完全就是普通的雞肉
Take its innards out and rub your spices on it.
除掉內臟後塗上香料
Stuff it with veggies and finely chopped herbs
將蔬菜與切碎的香草塞進腹部
and tie up the opening.
綁緊切口
Put a skewer through the meat
然後將肉串好
and roast it thoroughly.
用火仔細炙烤
It's done.
然後就完成了
Hurry, feed it to him.
快點，快拿給他吃
The meat's overflowing with juices. It's delicious.
肉汁豐富，相當好吃
Sorry about all that.
我感到很抱歉
You all should eat too.
你們也來吃吧
Hold on.
等一下
I got to cast a healing spell first…
我得先施治癒魔法…
This is so good! I could see this at a restaurant in town.
真好吃！好像鎮上餐廳的料理
It tastes exactly like chicken.
味道果然很像雞肉
I heard snake meat is similar to chicken too.
聽說蛇肉味道也很像雞肉
Sorry, I'll cast my healing spell now.
抱歉，我立刻用治癒魔法幫你療傷
Oops, wrong item.
糟糕，拿錯了
I've never had a proper meal like this before in a dungeon.
我還是第一次在迷宮吃到像樣的料理
Um…
想請問一下…
It's been three months since we started challenging this dungeon,
我們挑戰迷宮已經三個月了
but we keep getting wiped out at the same place.
可是每次都在同樣的地方全軍覆沒
How do we become strong enough to cook monsters like you all?
怎樣才能變得像你們一樣 強大到足以料理魔物呢？
Well, that's…
這個嘛…
First, improve your diet.
首先要改善飲食生活
Rethink your circadian rhythm.
重整生活作息
And engage in proper exercise.
再加上適當的運動
If you pay attention to these three things,
只要注意那三點
your body will naturally get stronger.
自然就能培養強健的體魄
What incredible people.
真是一群厲害的人
Let's do our best too.
我們也要好好加油
Reaching the third floor today might be impossible.
看來今天是不可能走到第三層了
It's because we took our sweet time on that roast.
因為花太多時間烤肉了
Apparently, the Red Dragon wakes up once a month to go hunting.
據說炎龍每個月會醒一次去狩獵
That was probably when we ran into it the other day.
前幾天我們會遇到炎龍 是因為正值那個時期
Then he's sleeping on a full stomach now.
所以牠現在應該已經吃飽 進入睡眠狀態了吧
I'd like to find him before he gets an empty stomach.
我想在炎龍再次空腹前找到牠
That's why, Marcille,
所以說啊，瑪露希爾
it'd be great if we could move things along.
我想稍微加快腳步
Won't be easy at this rate.
照這情況看來有點困難
I'm totally fine.
我沒事
I can easily walk more.
我還走得動
Don't push yourself.
你別逞強
Let's rest a bit.
休息一下吧
I'm not pushing myself!
我才沒有逞強呢！
Hey, listen.
喂，你給我聽好
If you try to act tough now,
你現在這樣虛張聲勢
you'll just hurt yourself and become a burden, got it?
萬一搞壞身體 反倒會變成絆腳石，懂嗎？
SHOCK
（受到打擊）
It might be easier to use a different path.
走別條路或許比較輕鬆
But the Big Bat outside will be in our way.
可是外頭有大蝙蝠在擋路
I can use magic on the Big Bats.
我可以用魔法對付大蝙蝠
No, that's okay.
不用，沒關係
What about a secret passageway?
不如使用隱藏通道如何？
More traps, but fewer monsters.
雖然陷阱多，不過魔物比較少
I have trap-disarming spells…
我可以施展解除陷阱魔法…
It's faster if Chilchuck disarms them.
交給奇爾查克來解除比較快
We're taking a path with fewer monsters, huh?
要走魔物較少的通道是吧？
We should secure some foodstuffs then.
老夫想確保食材
Can't we get by on today's leftovers?
不能靠中午的殘餚設法撐過去嗎？
We only have meat and eggs.
食材只剩下肉類和蛋
We need vegetables.
我們還需要一些蔬菜
There's a Mandrake colony near here.
附近有曼德拉草的群生地
Me! I know how to harvest Mandrakes!
交給我！我知道怎麼採收曼德拉草！
Leave it to me!
包在我身上！
Mandrakes are fundamental in magic and medicine.
曼德拉草是魔法與藥學的基礎
In other words, my area of expertise.
換句話說是我的專長領域
Everyone, listen to me this time.
各位，這次要遵照我的指示行動
Mandrakes scream when you pull them from the dirt.
曼德拉草拔出土壤時會發出慘叫
It'll make you go insane or even cause death.
聽到會令人精神錯亂，甚至致死
We would get wiped out
如此一來我們就會全滅
and be one step further from saving Falin.
離拯救法琳的目標又會變得更遠
To prevent that…
為了避免此情況發生…
First, we need a string and a well-trained dog.
首先準備好繩子及訓練有素的狗
A dog?
狗？
We'll tie the Mandrake to the dog's collar and call the dog over from a distance.
用繩子綁住狗的項圈及曼德拉草 接著站在遠方呼叫狗
Then, the Mandrake will be pulled out by the dog.
這麼一來曼德拉草 就會被狗順利拔出來
What'll happen to the dog?
那狗會怎麼樣？
It'll die.
會死掉
That's awful.
好殘忍啊
But also,
但這不是重點
where are we going to get a dog?
要上哪裡找狗？
And that method doesn't seem very efficient.
說到底那種方法未免也太沒效率了吧
But at school, we…
可是學校是這麼教我們的…
Can't we use a long string?
使用長繩來拔如何？
Huh?
什麼？
Use a string so long that we won't hear it scream.
使用長度可拉到聽不見慘叫聲的繩子
Then we won't need a dog.
這樣就不需要用到狗
What?
什麼？
I'm pretty sure we can't.
應該行不通
Maybe because it's hard to pull?
那樣可能會很難控制力道吧？
That scared me.
嚇我一跳
Was that Marcille?
原來是瑪露希爾的叫聲啊？
It won't scream if you cut its head off beforehand.
只要在曼德拉草發出叫聲前 砍掉頭部就不會出聲了
That's true.
說得也是
No, that's too dangerous.
不行，那麼做實在太危險了
That's how I've eaten them for many years.
長年來老夫就是 用這個方法吃曼德拉草
That kind of novice mentality brings the most danger.
那種外行人的判斷是最危險的
But Senshi actually has experience.
可是先西有多年實戰經驗
Have you ever tried the method according to the book?
你有試過書本寫的方法嗎？
No. I feel so bad for the dog.
沒有，因為狗實在太可憐了嘛
Either way, we don't have a dog nor the time for this.
無論如何，現在既沒有狗，也沒時間
Sorry, but let's learn how Senshi does it.
不好意思，我們要仿照先西的做法
If it were that easy,
如果那種簡單的方法可行的話
you'd think it'd be written in the handbook.
專門書上應該會有記載才對
But he's right.
不過他說得對
It's not convincing when I'm only reading from a book.
光靠書本上的知識的確缺乏說服力
I shouldn't have them do something I haven't tried myself.
要大家照自己 沒實踐過的做法也不太好
Something I haven't tried?
沒實踐過？
Then I'll just have to show them.
那我就實踐給他們看好了
I'll prove that my method makes sense.
我要證明這種做法才是合理的
I'm sorry, Marcille!
對不起，瑪露希爾！
I forgive you.
我原諒你們
But since I can't use a dog…
話雖如此，又不能用狗…
A monster!
魔物！
The monsters in this area are Big Bats.
說起這一帶的魔物就想到大蝙蝠
They should be asleep right now.
牠們現在應該在巢穴睡覺
I wonder if this will work.
我這樣做真的沒問題嗎？
It didn't say how hard you have to pull.
書上也沒提到施力大小
Big Bat nests can be found through their droppings.
大蝙蝠的巢穴可從有無糞便來判斷
Laios's library of knowledge is actually coming in handy.
沒想到萊歐斯的 冷知識居然派上用場了
And a place you can't hear the screams from
至於從這裡聽不到慘叫聲的場所
would be that tower.
就是那座塔
Focus on the target…
好好瞄準目標…
Aire Faum Orbis!
艾列法烏姆歐爾畢斯！
All right!
很好！
What's that?
什麼聲音？
Marcille?
瑪露希爾？
Wait.
等一下
Wait…
等等…
It really is important to try things first.
實踐真的非常重要
If anything,
至少呢
now I know why Big Bats shouldn't be used to replace dogs.
我終於明白不可用 大蝙蝠代替狗的原因了
Marcille!
瑪露希爾！
Did she die?
她死了嗎？
She's alive.
她還活著
Using a Big Bat instead of a dog?
居然用大蝙蝠代替狗？
What an idiot.
真笨啊
Hey, Marcille. Can you hear me?
喂，瑪露希爾，聽得到我說話嗎？
Yes, I am very well.
是，我很健康
No, you're not.
不，你看起來一臉糟糕
She heard the scream.
她聽到慘叫聲了
Let's keep talking with her.
繼續跟她搭話吧
She'll slowly snap out of it.
她應該就會逐漸恢復正常
Why did you do this?
你為什麼這麼做？
I panicked when I was told I'd be a burden,
被說是絆腳石讓我很焦慮
No wait…
抱歉…
…so I wanted to stick it to you guys and make you bow down to me.
為了還以顏色 讓你們對我下跪道歉才做出此舉
What the heck?
你這傢伙是怎樣？
Chilchuck.
奇爾查克
I felt alone since I couldn't be of help to everyone.
因為什麼忙都幫不上 無法幫助大家，讓我感到孤獨
The monsters get stronger as we go deeper into the dungeon.
越是深入迷宮，魔物也會越強
The thing I can depend on most is your magic,
最仰賴的就是你的魔法
so I didn't want to use it up on such an early floor.
因此我才想避免在迷宮淺層讓你疲累
And everyone has strengths and weaknesses.
再說每個人都有強項及弱項
I want to rely on your strengths.
遇到你的強項，我就會仰賴你
Someone else will cover for your weaknesses.
弱項就交給其他人解決
You can depend on us more.
你可以更加依賴我們喔
Tell her, Chilchuck.
來，奇爾查克也說幾句
I really think having you here with us is a huge help.
有瑪露希爾跟著真的幫了大忙
Put more feeling into it.
說話時再多放點感情
When did you get back to normal?!
你不是已經恢復正常了嗎？
I didn't expect a Big Bat too. What a surprising catch.
沒想到還能順便捕獲大蝙蝠 真是意外的收穫
How about we make some omelets today?
今天就來做歐姆蛋好嗎？
Is this really a Basilisk egg?
這真的是巴西利斯克的卵嗎？
It's completely different from chicken eggs.
跟雞蛋完全不同嘛
That's how snake eggs are.
蛇卵就是那麼軟
Only its tail was a snake.
牠只有尾巴是蛇
Its head and body were a chicken.
頭跟身體都是雞啊
No, the tail was a chicken.
不，雞是尾巴
BODY, TAIL
（本體，尾巴）
The color on this one is different from the rest.
只有這個跟其他色調不同
You're right.
真的耶
Marcille got that one since it still has a head.
還留著頭部的是瑪露希爾所採收的
Chop up the Mandrake and sauté it well.
將曼德拉草切丁，充分炒熟
Cover it with the egg.
接著用蛋包覆
Once it fluffs up…
煎得鬆鬆軟軟…
It's done.
就完成了
MANDRAKE AND BASILISK OMELET
（曼德拉草與巴西利斯克的歐姆蛋）
The yellow is way darker than a chicken egg.
比雞的蛋黃顏色還深
This is the Mandrake we harvested.
這盤用的是我們採收的曼德拉草
This one uses the Mandrake harvested by the elven girl.
另一盤用的則是 精靈女孩採收的曼德拉草
You shouldn't rub salt in someone's wound.
竟然還不放過我，真沒品
Now, now.
別這麼說
Marcille's isn't bitter, and it has a mild taste.
瑪露希爾採的曼德拉草 比較沒有澀味，相當醇厚
Yeah, it's delicious.
是啊，真好吃
The screaming must have gotten the bitterness out.
八成是透過慘叫去除澀味之類的吧
It's basic cooking knowledge that going the extra mile improves a dish.
多一道功夫讓味道變好吃 這是料理的基礎
It seems I only sought efficiency
看來老夫只顧追求效率
and lost sight of what truly matters.
卻迷失了本質
Thank you, Marcille.
要向你致謝才行，瑪露希爾
Your knowledge and book are superb.
你的知識與書本的內容都很出色
This isn't a cookbook, you know.
這不是食譜啦
Take this small gift as my thanks.
為了感謝你，這是一點心意
You can have the most delicious part.
享用最美味的部分吧
I don't want it!
不需要！
I'm sick and tired of eating monsters!
我受夠吃魔物了！
Is the shortcut entrance around here?
捷徑的入口是在這一帶嗎？
The entrance?
入口？
Laios, give me your sword.
萊歐斯，借用一下你的劍
It's here.
在這裡
What just happened?
剛才發生什麼事了？
Chilchuck is an expert in detecting traps and picking locks.
奇爾查克是發現陷阱及開鎖的專家
Just so you know, there will be traps everywhere,
話說在前頭，前方充滿陷阱
so don't do anything unless I tell you to.
在我下指令前不要輕舉妄動
What I hate the most
我最討厭的事
are those who get in the way of my work.
就是被人打擾工作
Hold it.
等等
These tiles are safe to step on.
這邊的地磚可以踩
What the heck was that?
你在幹什麼？
I told you to only step where I told you to.
我不是說過只能走我指示的地方嗎？
Your foot's sticking out by so much.
你的腳幾乎踩出界了
I don't like complicated stuff.
老夫不喜歡這種小花招
Who cares what you like?
現在是說這種話的時候嗎？
You've got to be more careful.
你隨意行動我會很困擾啦
Some traps are connected and affect other traps.
陷阱有連動式 相互影響式等眾多類型
If one thing shifts, all my calculations go out the window.
只要觸動一個陷阱 就會讓之前的計算前功盡棄
Just move wherever I tell you to.
你只需要照我說的行動就好
Such firepower.
好強的火力
I see.
原來如此
Traps come in many shapes and forms.
陷阱如此多樣化啊
Move your foot already.
快把你的腳挪開
Fire traps usually come as a set with gas or oil.
火焰陷阱旁邊 通常都會設有油或燃料的機關
Oil.
油
We don't need a dwarf roast.
我可不想看到火烤矮人
A roast.
火烤
No, wait.
不，等等
Deep-fried food.
炸雞
Fried.
炸…
Kakiage!
炸什錦！
We'll have tempura for lunch today.
今天的午餐就吃天婦羅吧
Where's the oil trap?
你剛剛說的油的機關在哪裡？
It's not meant for cooking.
鐵定不是食用油
Half-foot child.
半身人小孩
You are no expert on oil.
你又不是油的專家
I'm not a child.
我不是小孩
Vegetable oil is simple and the highest in supply.
植物油是最容易取得且供給最多的
Anyhow, show me the oil.
總之老夫想看實物
I'll give up if it isn't meant for cooking.
如果不是食用油，老夫就放棄
Fine.
好吧
In exchange,
作為交換條件
promise you'll follow my orders around the traps.
今後在陷阱旁一定要遵照我的指示
I won't help you if you don't accept this condition.
若不遵守這項條件我就不幫你
I swear it.
老夫發誓
I'll help too, if needed.
必要時老夫也會幫忙
I won't need it.
不需要
Listen.
聽好了
We each have our own job.
每個人各有專精
Yours is cooking. Mine is detecting traps and picking locks.
你負責料理，我負責解除陷阱與開鎖
Marcille's is magic.
瑪露希爾負責魔法
I don't say anything about your cooking methods.
我不會干預你的烹調方式
So, please stop interfering with my work.
所以你也別妨礙我的工作
The treasure vault.
寶物庫
The excessive number of traps here must be to keep out intruders.
陷阱會這麼多 是為了保護這裡不被人入侵吧
They're secured onto the ground.
箱子被固定在地板上
I guess I'll try opening one.
總之先打開看看吧
Go over there.
閃一邊去
He's usually the most mature one.
他平時明明是個性最沉穩的人
Having his companions' lives in his hands
畢竟現在同伴的命掌握在他手中
is probably putting him on edge.
導致他繃緊了神經吧
It's open.
打開了
I see. How do we get the oil out?
是喔，該怎麼取出油？
I don't know.
我不知道啦
This is the spout.
這是噴口
Pulling this trigger will release the oil, but I don't know how much.
只要扣下這扳機就會噴油 但是不確定會不會流很多
I'll have my pot ready then.
那麼老夫負責拿鍋子
Pull the trigger.
你負責扣扳機
No way.
我才不要
It's probably boiling oil.
這八成是沸騰的熱油
Don't be afraid.
別擔心
I am afraid.
我當然擔心啊
Don't come crying to me later!
如果出事可別怪我！
So hot!
好燙啊！
I told you so.
我早就說過了嘛
Are you okay, Senshi?
你沒事吧？先西
Your finger's in it!
手指居然插進油鍋！
It's 180 degrees. Perfect for frying food.
油溫180度，非常適合油炸呢
You're the type that's okay with heat?
原來你不怕燙啊？
The smell and taste tell me that it's olive oil.
依這股香味及味道來看，是橄欖油
For real?
真的假的？
They do say this area originally produced olives.
據說這一帶原是橄欖的產地
It's not surprising that it's used in traps.
會用來當作陷阱也不奇怪
You think so?
是嗎？
Either way, I can fry food with this.
總而言之，這樣就能做炸物了
Oh, right!
啊，對了！
Can we use the blade from the trap earlier to cut the meat?
可以利用剛才落下的 刀刃陷阱來切肉嗎？
No, we don't know if it'll fall in the exact same place.
不，可是那種陷阱又不一定 會落在同樣的地方
I'll leave it to you.
這部分就交給你負責
After all, I don't know how to handle the traps.
因為老夫不懂如何操作陷阱
Why should I?
為何我得做那種事？
Cooking is my job, so you should follow my directions.
料理是老夫負責的工作 所以你要遵照我的指令
I believe that was our deal.
那是我們說好的交換條件
I never said that.
我沒說過耶
What am I doing?
我到底在幹什麼啊？
I cut the Big Bat.
大蝙蝠已經切好了
Okay.
好
Next, go heat up this oil at the fire trap from earlier.
接著將這鍋油拿到 剛才的火焰陷阱加熱
What's wrong? Hurry along.
怎麼了？還不快去
Cut off the Big Bat's thick outer layer and chop the meat into chunks.
將大蝙蝠的皮厚切剝除後剁塊
Lightly score the meat,
表面稍微劃幾刀
massage the seasoning in, and let it rest.
以調味料搓揉，放置一會兒
Meanwhile, let's prepare the Mandrake kakiage.
在此期間進行曼德拉草炸什錦的備料
When you peel the Mandrake skin,
剝除曼德拉草的皮時
it's best to pull the limbs off first.
最好先拉斷手腳部位
You can tear them off by hand if you unravel them.
解開打結部分後就能用手擰斷
Completely peel the body
身體部分的皮要刮乾淨
and lightly scrape the darker parts off the limbs.
輕輕刮除手腳深色部分的皮
Then, we prepare the batter.
接下來做麵衣
Mix a Basilisk egg into the water
在水中將巴西利斯克的卵攪散後
and sift flour into the mixture.
篩入麵粉
Avoid clumps while mixing it
攪拌至沒有結塊後
and put the Mandrake in.
將曼德拉草倒入麵糊中
How's the fire going?
火候如何？
How would I know?
我怎麼知道？
I've never had to adjust a trap's firepower before, darn it.
我是第一次調整陷阱的火力，可惡
Looks just right.
這不是恰到好處嗎？
When it looks like it won't fall apart, flip it.
炸到麵團不會散開的程度就翻面
Got it?
懂了嗎？
Okay.
懂了
Is it ready?
可以翻面了吧？
Dang it. It was too soon.
糟了，時機尚早
Maybe the fire's too weak.
可能是因為火力太小
It burned.
炸焦了
How's it looking?
狀況如何？
It's going horribly. Can you take it from here?
糟糕透了，換你來吧
The fire trap is your job.
火焰陷阱是你該負責的部分
I can adjust the fire, but isn't frying part of your job?
姑且不論火力 調整油炸程度是料理的範疇吧
It turns gooey if the fire is weak,
火力太小會炸得黏糊糊的
but it burns if it's too strong.
要是太強則會馬上炸焦
That must mean it's not a trap-related issue, huh?
那就跟陷阱不相關呢
Looks almost ready.
炸得差不多囉
The color turned out nicely.
炸出漂亮的顏色了
It's done.
大功告成
MANDRAKE AND BIG BAT KAKIAGE
（曼德拉草炸什錦及大蝙蝠天婦羅）
I never imagined I could eat fried food in a dungeon like this.
想不到在迷宮內竟能吃到炸物
It's fried really well.
炸得很酥脆
We had a good firepower.
因為火力剛剛好
You must aim to fry food quickly with the right temperature.
炸物必須在適當油溫迅速油炸
It gets nice and crispy.
如此便能炸得酥脆
That's pretty hard to do with an open fire.
用篝火就很難炸得這麼好
I don't think people would do this on an open fire.
沒人會想用篝火炸東西吧
I pass by here often, but who knew such a convenient room was here?
老夫常在這一帶走動 想不到竟有如此便利的房間
Listen up.
話說在前頭
Don't try this without me here.
我不在時不准隨便亂試
You'll die for sure.
肯定會出人命
I know.
老夫明白
I can never imitate your trap manipulation skills.
你操作陷阱的技術無人能模仿
It's truly amazing.
真的非常傑出
When we go our separate ways someday,
一想到將來跟你們分別後
it's unfortunate that I won't be able to use that trap alone.
再也不能獨自操作 那道陷阱就覺得遺憾
I guess I have no choice.
真拿你沒辦法
When we have some spare time,
今後有空時
I'll teach you a bit about traps.
我會稍微教你有關陷阱的知識
Are you sure?
可以嗎？
I'm kind of reluctant to do so.
雖然不大情願
But you know, you taught me how to cook, Senshi.
不過你也有教我如何料理
Bread cannot replace meat.
麵包無法取代肉
Nor can meat replace bread.
肉也無法取代麵包
But together, they taste even better.
不過兩者一起搭配會更美味
Both food and people remain the same.
人與食物沒什麼不同
Dungeon food.
迷宮飯
Subtitle translation by: Chul Kim
字幕翻譯：黃琳雅